Kuang-Yao Dennis Liu

Sr SAS Programmer in Pharma/ Clinical Trail

tassy_520@hotmail.com

Summary

A quick learner, I pick up things quickly. A good analyst, I list every possibility and then trim it back to the best ones. My self-confidence, my communication, my attitude, my leadership, quality and deliver of work completion in time are my strength of success.

I have used SAS over 7 years, and I enjoy what I do!

Specialties: statistical analysis, data manipulate, clinical research, clinical trial

Experience

Principal Statistical Programmer at Covance

May 2012 - Present (4 years 2 months)

Lead and provide hands-on support to the design, development, and quality control process for SAS code used to access, extract, transform, review, analyze, and submit data for multiple studies and clinical development programs.

Senior Statistical Analyst at Sanofi Pasteur

September 2011 - May 2012 (9 months)

- Act as lead programmer to organize and prioritize work to develop specific goals to accomplish project objectives
- Produce SDTM and ADaM datasets and specification in the Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP).
- Execute analyses specified in the SAP under the guidance of the project statistician.
- Validate SAS programs that produce datasets and analyzed result
- Provide submission preparation and QC support for dataset section of submissions to ensure submission readiness
- Track all variables to source/origin and ensure documented clearly either on annotated CRF, external data documentation, or analysis dataset documentation.

Programer II at PAREXEL

February 2009 - August 2011 (2 years 7 months)

Responsibilities include assisting in the coordination of project start-up activities, including Unix/PMED project area set-up, creation of global programs (e.g., setup.sas, formats.sas, etc.), tracking spreadsheets, and required documentation, assisting the production and QC of derived dataset specifications, programming specifications, and other process supporting documents, and using efficient programming techniques to

produce and/or QC low-medium complexity derived datasets, tables, figures and data listings, creating, implementing and maintaining consistency checks in standard or CDISC format for database builds in CDMS and EDC, following and understanding internal and external regulatory requirements, creating, implementing and executing import and export programs, in either standard format, client specific format or CDISC compliant format depending on nature of request, and performing small ad-hoc programming tasks.

SAS Programmer / RA at Academia Sinica

October 2007 - December 2008 (1 year 3 months)

Worked on association and linkage analyses on psychological genetic. Almost all works have done on UNIX and LINUX environment and some analyses done by SAS/genetics package on window environment.

Database Programmer at National Yang Ming University

July 2007 - October 2007 (4 months)

- Used Perl regular expressions to find special and meaningful DNA sequence pattern
- Maintained and improved two online biomedical databases

Assistant at National Defense Medical Center

January 2004 - June 2005 (1 year 6 months)

I did my military service in NDMC. I was assigned to be an assistant of Dr. Oliver Yoa-Pu Hu who is former director of Bureau of Pharmaceutical Affairs. My responsibilities are to execute his order precisely and assist to setup some conferences and scientific seminars.

Courses

Programer II

PAREXEL

Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt Certified

Languages

English

(Professional working proficiency)

Mandarin

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

SAS

Unix Shell Scripting

Perl

CDISC

SAS/SQL

EDC

Clinical Trials

Clinical Research
Statistical Programming
CRO
Biostatistics
SDTM
Clinical Data Management
Clinical Development
Statistics
SAS programming
SAS Programming

Education

Washington University School of Medicine in St. Louis

Master, Genetic Epidemiology, 2005 - 2006

Activities and Societies: President of Taiwanese Graduate Students Association

National Taiwan University B.S., Agronomy, 1999 - 2003

Interests

running, international travel

Kuang-Yao Dennis Liu

Sr SAS Programmer in Pharma/ Clinical Trail

tassy_520@hotmail.com



1 person has recommended Kuang-Yao Dennis

"Dennis is the one of the brightest person I've ever met. He is a great team player who always accomplishes the assigned tasks in a timely manner, and a dependable leader who always communicates proactively across internal functional departments. His proficiency in SAS/UNIX programmings, excellence in problem solving, and solid understanding in clinical trials set him apart from others in the field. He is a great asset to PAREXEL and I highly recommend him to any organizations."

— Vicky Chiang, worked directly with Kuang-Yao Dennis at PAREXEL

Contact Kuang-Yao Dennis on LinkedIn